In that year before 9/11 at the CIA, we
were panicstricken
because we knew a major attack was
coming and we had no idea when it would.
I I blew the whistle on the CIA's
torture program in 2007. Oh, you go to
prison, everybody's innocent. Yeah, you
know what? A lot of people are innocent.
The intent was not to go to war with
Afghanistan. What was the intent?
>> The intent was to destroy al-Qaeda. And
correct me if I'm wrong, the
Palestinians welcomed the Israelis or
the Jews, the European Jews, the
Ashkenazi Jews with open arms, as in
come here. This is a safe haven for you.
>> That's exactly right. And then the Nakba
took place. If you're in government,
especially if you're in intelligence,
you know from the get-go, the Israelis
are no friends of ours. President Trump
released the rest of the JFK documents.
He released most of them. And I said,
"Well, why didn't he release all of
them?" and he said, "Because the ones
that are still classified point the
finger right at the Israelis."
[Music]
What is up everybody? Welcome back to
the Wise Nuts podcast channel. Uh we
want to thank every single one of you
who are tuning in today and uh for all
the support that you've been showing us
for the past couple months now. Our
channel's growing and if you haven't,
we're about 5 seconds in. Click that
like button, subscribe to our channel.
It helps us grow and it helps us bring
amazing guests to the podcast where we
could sit down, have great
conversations. And we have one hell of a
conversation that we're going to be
taking place today with one heck of a
guest as well.
>> Yeah, for sure. And don't and don't
forget to comment as well because when
you guys comment, you get to engage with
one another. It helps the algorithms
like Orno mentioned, it increases the
views and in return, we can bring on
bigger and bigger guests.
>> We grow. We all grow together at the end
of the day. But uh all the way from the
other side of the United States, Mr.
John Kiryaku is here with us.
>> Thanks for having me.
>> How was the flight in?
>> Tough,
>> was it?
>> You know, no big deal. I I don't mind
getting up early. It What I hate are
unnecessary delays and the first half
was easy as pie. The second half you're
just sitting there.
>> Yeah. I know you mentioned something
about
sitting on the tarmac and they're
waiting on literally a mesh that was
>> a mesh net
>> that that had to be replaced.
>> Yeah. For over an hour. Like where are
they going to find a mesh net?
>> But the best part of it is they gave him
half a can of Coke in the airplane
>> and we gave him two two cans of cans of
Coke.
>> Yeah.
>> Coca-Cola sponsorship. You know, I was
thinking today actually, how many
thousands of miles have you flown? Let's
say in the last 20, 30 years.
>> Oh my god. I can tell you in the 9
months after 9/11,
I flew a million miles. And it took me
15 years to use up those miles.
Yeah. I went on my honeymoon, first
class to Argentina. I was burning miles
all the time because you're traveling
all around the world. I went to 72
countries. most of them right after 911.
>> And so, you know what? An old-timer told
me back in the 90s, he said, "Uh, you
know, they got these things now, these,
uh, frequent flyer miles." I said,
"Yeah, I heard about these, right?" And
he says, "Uh, you should, uh, sign up
for them for all the airlines." I said,
"Why? We're not allowed to keep the
miles." Cuz back then the rule was that
the CIA owned the miles,
>> right? So, they got to use the free
tickets. And he said, "They're going to
change that rule. That's a stupid rule.
it's inevitable that they're going to
change it. So, I started I I signed up
for all the airlines and started
accumulating miles, never used them, and
sure enough, right before 911, they
changed the rules. They said, "Ah,
everybody can keep their miles."
>> A million miles,
>> they sent me They sent me like a a
platinum. It wasn't platinum. It was
black a black card in a wooden box
>> cuz I was like premium diamond special
status. Every time I got on the plane,
I'd get upgraded to first class and that
only lasted a couple of years, but yeah,
>> still it was pretty nice.
>> When did you get out of jail, Jonah?
>> Uh, February 3rd of 2015.
>> And for for those of for those of you
tuning in or the guests or the viewers
that are watching this, can we go back
in time very quickly and just very very
quickly just dabble on what was the
reason why you went to jail?
>> Yeah. So, I went to I I blew the whistle
on the CIA's torture program in 2007.
Patently illegal, besides being immoral
and unethical, I went public, blew the
whistle on it. I so enraged the CIA's
leadership
that they they reported me to the FBI
for revealing classified information.
This was December of 2007.
The FBI investigated me until December
of 2008 and then they concluded I had
not committed a crime. They closed the
case. Three weeks later, Barack Obama
becomes president. John Brennan John and
I have always hated each other. John
Brennan becomes the deputy national
security adviser for counterterrorism,
later CIA director. John asks the
Justice Department to secretly reopen
the case against me. And so they
investigated me for three more years. I
had no idea. But wait, the case was
closed though. It's
>> closed.
>> So, double jeopardy?
>> No, because I was never charged. If I
had been charged and then they elected
to not prosecute, that would have been
double jeopardy.
>> So,
I had no idea. My phones were tapped. My
emails were being intercepted. Teams of
FBI agents are following me everywhere I
was going. Into church, into my kids
school to drop them off, Target,
restaurants with my family. We always
had teams of FBI agents on us that we
never paid attention to. And then they
charged me with five felonies in January
of 2012, including three counts of
espionage.
I hadn't committed espionage, of course.
What's the definition of espionage?
>> It's very simple. It's providing
national defense information to any
person not entitled to receive it.
>> So, how was that espionage
>> exactly? How is that espionage? I went
on ABC News. I said the CIA is torturing
its prisoners. Oh, espionage.
That's that's not [__] espionage.
>> Unless it's not CIA agents who are
torturing, it's somebody else who's
torturing and
>> right,
>> you're giving intellect. But you would
think that the that the definition of
espionage that we all know, you know,
providing classified information to a
foreign government, that's espionage.
What Biden did with Ukraine and China is
espionage. No, allegedly providing
>> Thank god you said allegedly.
>> You could you could make that argument.
Um, but anyway, what they did is they
they waited until I went bankrupt.
Before we started filming, we were
having a conversation about legal fees
and I ran up about a million and a
quarter in legal fees. I went bankrupt
and then they dropped all the espionage
charges. So, they said, "Well, take a
take a guilty plea to a lesser offense
and and we'll just close the case." So,
I decided not to. I decided to turn it
down. and they finally gave me what they
called their best and final offer. They
were they were trying to get me to
accept 45 years in prison. I said, "I'm
not going to do 45 minutes. I'm going to
fight you to the bitter end." And then
they came down to 10 and then to 8 and
then to five. And my lead attorney said,
"You know, I've been an attorney in
Washington for 52 years and I've never
seen them come down in time." I said,
"Why are why are they coming down?" He
said, "Well, usually they'll offer you
10 and if you say no, the next offer is
15 and then 20." So I said, "Why are
they coming down?" He said, "Because
they have a [__] case and they know it's
[__] and that's why we're going to
trial." Well, I believed him. We're
going to trial. We're going to fight
this thing. So they they make a best and
final offer. 2 and 1/2 years. I do 23
months
>> from 20 to 2 and 1/2.
>> From 45 to 2 and 1/2. So, so, so from 45
to 2 and 1/2 years.
>> And I said, "No,
I'm not doing it." I said, "I didn't do
anything wrong. I'm going to fight you."
So, I emailed the lawyer 6:00 in the
morning. I said, "I I've been up all
night with my wife. We're talking about,
you know, what we should do. I didn't do
anything wrong. I'm going to trial." And
one of the attorneys says, "Put on a pot
of coffee. We're on our way over." So,
they get to my house 7:00 in the
morning. and the one that was an an
attorney for 52 years, he was the first
one through the door and he says, "You
stupid son of a [__] Take the deal." I
said, "You're the one who told me not to
take the deal." He said, "I only said
that to keep your morale up."
So the other ones, there were four like
lead attorneys. I had 11 attorneys
altogether. This was a major national
security case. Like every time there was
a development, it'd be on the front page
of the Washington Post, the front page
of the New York Times. people are
writing editorials about it. So, uh the
second lawyer who was a real like
southern gentleman,
beautifully dressed all the time, just a
lovely guy, he he says to me, "Look, if
if you were my brother, I would beg you
to take this deal. Just take the deal."
And I said, "But I didn't do anything
wrong. And I have five kids. I can't
just like go to prison just like that
and just walk away from everybody and
let them fend for themselves.
And then the third attorney pulls me
aside and he was a little bit angry and
I actually liked and respected him the
most and he said, "You know what your
problem is? Your problem is you think
this is about justice and it's not about
justice. It's about mitigating damage.
Take the deal."
So I said, "Well, if I don't take the
deal and I'm found guilty, what am I
realistically looking at?" And they
said, "12 to 18 years. Take the deal."
So I took it. And I I say all the time,
you know, there's this ongoing joke.
Everybody knows this joke that, oh, you
go to prison, everybody's innocent.
Yeah. You know what? A lot of people are
innocent.
But the government does this thing. They
do two things strategies called one's
called charge stacking where let's say
you actually did something right. They
won't charge you just with one thing.
They'll charge you with 20 felonies and
they'll wait until you go bankrupt and
then they say, "All right, we'll dismiss
19 of them if you take a guilty plea."
Well, maybe you actually didn't do it,
but you're looking at a hundred years in
prison. And you know the old saying that
that an a jury will will convict a
bologn sandwich if the bologn sandwich
is on trial, right? People say all the
time, "Well, if they were innocent, the
cops wouldn't have arrested them in the
first place." That's not the system we
have. The system that we have is that
you're innocent until proven guilty.
>> Correct.
>> Not when you're facing the government.
And that is why the government wins
98.2% of their cases. You can't afford
to fight the government. That's the
difference.
>> It's not. That's true. But it's not only
that. For example, in healthcare, you
work with the government, right? If
you're
>> being paid by Medicare, Medicaid, medic,
whoever, technically you work for the
government.
>> Sure.
>> Not
like a contractor.
>> Exactly. Exactly. Yeah.
>> And their approach, and I've asked them
this. I've asked several people who work
for CMS. I said, "So, we as providers
of Medicare are guilty until proven
innocent."
>> Absolutely.
>> You're like, "Unfortunately,
>> that's what it comes down to."
>> I said, "How?" I thought we're innocent
till proven guilty. But with anything
related to government, you're not.
>> You know, I had this judge in my case,
too. This little tiny [__] she's like
4 foot 10, and she was a Clinton
appointee. M
>> and uh
my my attorneys, here's how good my
attorneys were. They negotiated
something called an 11C1C plea. Um which
means it it's written in stone and the
judge can't change it. So I agreed to
plead guilty. The government agreed to
30 months. I do 23 11 C1C. The judge
when I went to my sentencing, she said,
"I've been a judge for years and I have
never seen an 11C1C plea. This is my
first one," she says. And she looks at
me and she says, "I don't like it. And I
don't like it one bit. I wish I could
give you 10 years," she says. Well, the
truth is she could have. All she had to
do is say, "No, I don't I don't respect
the 11c plea. go back to the negotiating
table, come up with something else.
That's all she had to say. But every
national security journalist in America
was in the courtroom that day to see
what I was going to get. And so she had
to make it look like she was tough and
she was going to stand up. Okay, that
was that was October of 2012.
There are others who have come after me.
Jeffrey Sterling, CIA whistleblower. Uh
Daniel um what's Daniel's last name? Uh
um anyway, the drone whistleblower,
Daniel Hail, the drone whistleblower and
and others, Ed Snowden. And so I'll give
you an example. I was in I was in Daniel
Hail's sentencing hearing
and the Justice Department didn't see
that I was sitting directly behind them
in the first row with an NSA
whistleblower, Tom Drake. We all stick
together. We have a community now,
right? So
Daniel went to trial, which was very,
very brave. And he's the one that said
that we were killing civilians with
drones. And the reason why he decided to
blow the whistle, I'll give you just as
a little bit of background. It's a very
sad story. You know, we operate these
drones are the the Air Force, the Army,
the CIA, whoever, whoever has drones,
they operate them mostly from here,
right? you're you're in some office
building in outside of Las Vegas or at
at some air base in Florida or whatever
and it's all by computer, right? And
you're guiding these these drones in
Afghanistan or Somalia or Iraq or
wherever they happen to be. So Daniel's
following this alleged terrorist in in a
car and the guy pulls the car over and
gets out of the car and Daniel's on the
secure comms with his boss who's at
McDill Air Force Base in in Tampa.
And he says, "I I see the target." And
the boss says, "Fire." And he said,
"Wait a minute. There are two little
kids with him." And the boss says,
"Those aren't kids. Those are goats. He
said, "I'm looking at them. They're two
little girls."
And the guy says, "Fire."
And Daniel says, "I can't fire. He's
with two little kids." And the guy says,
"Fire or be court marshaled."
>> This is straight up from the movie
Scarface.
>> Yeah, it's terrible. And so he fired.
>> Are you kidding me?
>> And he killed them. And he went home. He
told me that that that he went home that
day and he told his housemate, "I became
a child killer today.
You've seen the movie Scarface, right?
>> Yes, I have.
>> Just want to make sure because he hasn't
se We'll we'll get to the Matrix later.
It's a powerful movie
>> because in the movie Scar literally what
you're telling me with Daniel is exactly
what was happening with
>> uh Tony.
>> Yeah.
>> Or where he had to blow up that car.
>> Yeah. Where the two kids were in the
car.
>> Kids were in the car
>> and he couldn't pull the trigger where
he obviously killed the uh
>> Yeah.
>> the guy who had the trigger with him.
That's right.
>> Wow.
>> So, so I'm in the I'm in the gallery.
I'm one row behind the prosecutors
and uh and Daniel's found guilty of of
telling The Intercept and a a a
documentary filmmaker on PBS that we've
got a drone program and we kill
civilians with the drone program. They
were like, "Ah, classified. You can't
say that. You're under arrest."
So
the justice department says, "Your
honor, we we're asking that you sentence
him to 10 years."
And the this is a different judge, kind
of a a wise, you know, older
judge who saw what the Justice
Department was doing here. And u the
judge says, "I I can't give him 10
years." When Kiryaku got two and a half,
he said, "I'll give you Kiryaku." or the
the pro the the defense said, "How about
Kiryaku plus 12 months because I took a
plea, he went to trial and you're
punished if you go to trial, right? It's
called failure to accept
responsibility." So, they increase your
sentence if you go if you exercise your
constitutional right
>> cuz you're fighting the system. That's
why.
>> That's right. And they make you pay.
>> So, the Justice Department's like, "No,
no. Um, Sterling got Kuryaku plus 12.
It's going to have to be Kiryaku plus,
you know, 60.
And And I'm sitting right there and this
Washington Post reporter looks at me and
he says, "What do you make of this?" I
said, "He's going to get screwed. He's
going to get screwed." And the judge is
like, "Enough enough of this talk." He
says, "I'm going to do" and the judge
didn't know me. He He didn't recognize
me, but he says, "I'll do Kuryaku plus
24."
And then I I went up to Daniel
afterwards
and uh he was distraught as you might
imagine and I said, "Buddy," I said,
"This was a major victory for you." I
said, "What they're not telling you, and
this is what I learned in prison, is
that
um you're entitled to 10 to 15% of your
time off for good behavior. You're
entitled to up to 10% of your time in a
halfway house or home confinement.
And if you tell them that you have a
drug or alcohol problem, they'll send
you they'll send you to something called
ARDAP, the residential drug and alcohol
program. You get another 12 months off.
So I said, "Don't worry, you're not
going to be in prison for 4 and a half
years."
>> Yeah.
>> And sure enough, he got out at around
two.
>> There's no There's no How long
>> were you in prison?
>> I was in for 23 months.
>> But you actually You did the full 23.
>> I did every day of it. They [__] me at
every opportunity. And I told them, I
said, "Listen, I have lived in far worse
places than your prison in Lorettto,
Pennsylvania. So, it's not like you guys
are intimidating me in any way."
>> See, John, I want to know this. Why is
it that you, as the whistleblower, were
sentenced to 23 months in jail?
>> Yep.
>> For whistleblowing. Yep.
>> But the individuals who made the who
called the shots,
>> there it is right there,
>> are serving nothing at all.
>> No. And in fact, they all literally all
of them went on to multi-million dollar
book deals.
>> Oh, really? The book deals? Huh? That's
where it was.
>> My my big complaint uh to answer your
question specifically is that we have a
whistleblower protection law in the
United States, but national security
whistleblowers are not protected by it.
So, if you work for the CIA, the FBI,
Pentagon, NSA, you're screwed. I
mentioned Tom Drake a minute ago.
>> Yes.
>> Tom uh was was one of the early
whistleblowers. Uh right after 911, he
blew the whistle on um on a a program at
NSA that NSA instituted that started
collecting the communications of
American citizens, which was against the
law. And um they charged him with nine
felonies, seven counts of espionage,
two counts of theft of government
property. You know what the property
was? It was the information. He walked
out of the building with the information
in his head.
>> How many counts for
>> Seven counts of espionage and two counts
of theft?
>> For government theft.
>> Yeah. He
>> all because it was in his head.
>> He stole the information. It was in his
head and he walked out of the building
with it.
>> Nice. Right. So, get this. Um
they they raid his house. They take all
of his um electronics, everything, and
then they go to his wife, who's also at
NSA, and they say, "We're raiding your
house and arresting your husband right
now as we speak. You're either with him
or you're with us and she was with
them."
>> So, they gave her an ultimatum.
>> And that's totally legal, right?
>> Absolutely. So, he plead not guilty and
he fought it and fought it and fought
it. Why did he fight it? Because what
they teach us to do is if you see waste,
fraud, abuse, illegality, or threats to
the public health or public safety,
that's the definition of whistleblowing.
First, you go to your boss. Tom went to
his boss. Boss told him, "Buddy, this is
this is way above your pay grade. You
need to walk away." Then he went to the
uh general counsel and the general
counsel said, "This is none of your
business. You need to stop." Then he
went to the inspector general. The
inspector general wasn't read into the
compartment. So the inspector general
said, "I don't know what you're talking
about." Then he went to the Pentagon
inspector general because NSA is a DoD
um agency.
They ratted him out to the NSA
leadership and said, "Hey, you have a
loose cannon. This guy's out talking to
people about this program."
Then he went to the House Intelligence
Committee, which is the oversight
committee, and said they're committing
illegalities. They grab him and charge
him with nine felonies. He was facing 90
years in prison. And so, literally the
night before the trial began,
the case fell apart and they had to drop
all the charges
because he hadn't committed espionage.
How so how does the whole um
whistleblower protection law play into
this? Because you know in 1778 that law
was passed after the
>> first whistleblow incident in 1777 right
against the right same situation as
yours where the uh
>> British um prisoners of wars Yes. were
being tortured
>> were being tortured. Well, if you work
for the Department of Agriculture
>> Mhm.
>> or the Department of Labor or the, you
know, Federal Trade Commission,
God bless, you're fully protected. You
go to Senator Grassly or, you know, or
Congressman Jordan, you fill out the
form, they say, "Oh my god, you're being
discriminated against. We're going to
protect your job." If you work for the
intelligence community, you're screwed.
There's literally nothing that you can
do to protect yourself. I met with a guy
yesterday. I'm not going to say who he
is. Yesterday was a Saturday
and an attorney reached out to me and
said, "Look, I represent an intelligence
community whistleblower. He's scared to
death and he just needs to talk to
somebody." I said, "Done." So, we met in
one of these like
office buildings where you rent a
conference room by the hour, you know? I
was there for three and a half hours and
I just let the guy vent and he came with
thousands of pages of documents. He's
laying out the case. I said, "Buddy, you
don't have to convince me of the case. I
know that you're telling the truth. I
know it. You don't have to convince me,
but uh he said, "I just I need somebody
to talk to because I feel like I'm going
crazy." And I said, 'Yeah, you're going
to feel like you go cra like you're
going crazy, but rely on your attorneys
and cultivate friendly voices in the
media. And I said, if you have an
opening to Senator Chuck Grassley of
Iowa, talk to Grassly. He's a friendly
ear. Otherwise, don't trust anybody
because the FBI knows what you're doing
most likely, and they're going to try to
get you to implicate yourself. I said, '
Even talking to me is a risk. He and I
had never met. You know, I could be an
FBI agent undercover. I mean, of course,
I'm not. I'm I'm sort of a public
figure, but I said, don't talk to
anybody without your lawyer sitting in
the chair next to you.
>> Have you been involved in a car
accident? Don't face the aftermath
alone. Arman Gregorian is your personal
injury attorney who specializes in car
accidents. He'll fight for compensation
that you deserve. Call Arman Gregorian
now at 818-44333.
That's 818-44333.
Our insurance companies giving you the
runaround. Stop stressing and start
winning. Public assist goes toe-to-toe
with the insurance companies so you can
get paid every single dollar that you
deserve. Fire damage, water damage,
storm damage. Has a tree gone through
your house? Public Assist has your back.
Don't wait. Call them today.
818-24299818242998.
>> The CIA was founded in 1947.
>> Mhm. With the passage of the National
Security Act of 194
>> and they replaced the OSS.
>> Correct.
>> So what was the purpose behind replacing
the OSS? It was like there there was
>> you had a central intelligence agency
>> at the time. Why replace it and
officially call it the central
intelligence?
>> OSS was the office of strategic
services. Correct. So what it did for
the most part was it it parachuted
Americans behind German lines in the
second world war. So what they did is
for example I'm Greek American. A lot of
early OSS guys were Greek Americans who
spoke Greek. They would parachute behind
Nazi lines into Greece, speak Greek,
look like Greeks, and then, you know,
blow up bridges and stuff so that the
Nazis couldn't get their supplies. So,
it was Greeks and Italians and a lot of
German Jews. So, they were Jews who
spoke German but could pass as German
citizens. Yeah.
>> And it was mostly um sabotage.
>> So, after 1945, all of a sudden with the
dropping of the two atomic bombs, we're
a superpower. We had never been a
superpower before. And the British
convinced President Truman, you need a
serious intelligence service. You don't
have one. OSS essentially ceased to
exist once the war ended. Everybody just
went back to Wall Street and they went
back to their law firms and their jobs
that they were doing. And so, um,
so Truman asked the British, um, MI6
station chief in New York, it's funny,
he wasn't even in Washington, he was in
New York, to help us create this
organization that's going to be the
central repository for all analysis and
operations. We're going to call it the
Central Intelligence Agency. There was
serious push back by Jay Edgar Hoover at
the FBI and um Hoover said uh we don't
need any CIA. I can be the head of both
the FBI and the CIA. CIA should be part
of the FBI.
and Hoover started going to Capitol Hill
to try to to convince important members
of Congress to vote against this
National Security Act which also created
um the National Security Council. So
Truman
told a lie which was very important
historically. He called Hoover in and he
said, "You're right. We're going to
create this CIA and it's going to be a
division of the FBI, but you've got to
go back to the Hill and tell everybody
to vote yes.
Well, there was never any intention to
make the CIA an adjunct of the FBI. And
so, the National Security Act of 47 was
passed. Truman signed it into law. The
CIA was created. Hoover was humiliated.
And so the CIA and the FBI, for all
intents and purposes, never cooperated
between 1947
and the 9/11 attacks.
And in 1949, Mossad was created.
>> Correct. So I want to ask you this. Is
it a coincidence that in 1948 you have
the CIA created and then in 1949 you
have MSAD created? Did they work hand in
hand together or are they completely two
separate different agencies? Oh, they're
they're two separate agencies and we've
never been as close with the Mossad as
we are with say the Five Eyes, the other
four partners of the Five Eyes. Uh five
eyes are US, UK, Canada, Australia, New
Zealand.
>> Yes.
>> But uh yeah, the uh the CIA and MI6 and
by all accounts the KGB
jumped in to train Mossad. Keep in mind
also that Mossad was different than all
these other intelligence services
because the Israelis couldn't lose. If
they if they were to lose, everybody
dies. They're going to be pushed into
the sea, right? So, they didn't have
rules and laws like all these other
services had.
>> So, how much influence does Mossad have
on the CIA and US foreign policies?
It's not specifically the Mossad that
has influence over foreign policy. It's
the the Israel lobby in the form of Apac
and very wealthy Jewish Americans. You
know, and and that wasn't even really
the case until the Nixon administration.
You know, I heard something the other
day from a from a history professor that
I never I had never heard this before.
We were talking about the founding of
Israel and he said, "You know how Israel
was founded?" I said, "Yeah, of course."
You know, the Truman administration and
the United Nations and blah blah. He
said, "No, it was $2 million in a
briefcase that was delivered to the
Truman um campaign train in 1948."
I said, "No, I I didn't know that." He
said, "Yeah, Truman really didn't care
if if European Jews had a homeland or
not. That was a British problem. But 2
million in cash in a briefcase, that's
going to make him interested."
Truman, you can find on YouTube. Truman
gave a statement that he knew that he
was successful creating Israel when both
sides came out of it hating him. But
that wasn't really true.
>> By both sides? What do you mean by both
sides?
>> The Palestinians and the Jews.
>> Really? I thought it would be the
opposite. I thought the Palestinians
would hate him and the Jews would like
him.
>> They love them.
>> But the but the Jews wanted all of it.
They didn't want it divided, you know,
into Palestine and Israel or or
Palestine mandate.
>> And correct me if I'm wrong, the
Palestinians welcomed the Israelis or
the Jews, the European Jews, the
Ashkenazi Jews with open arms, as in
come here.
>> This is a safe haven for you.
>> That's exactly right. And then the Nagba
took place
and everything changed and it's never
gone back.
>> And the Nagba is the Israeli Palestinian
war.
>> Correct.
Correct. where where you know hundreds
and hundreds of thousands of
Palestinians fled mostly to Jordan
thinking we'll regroup, we'll fight our
war and we'll reclaim our land and here
we are five generations later and
they're still in Jordan. It's John.
We've had this conversation with other
guests before where we talk about that
specific territory, that specific land.
Whether you want to call it Palestine or
you want to call it Israel, it doesn't
matter. But when you look at the history
behind it and the people who were the
original settlers, the people who were
there 3,000 years ago,
>> right?
>> Whether they were Muslim, whether they
were Christian, or whether they were
Jewish,
>> when you talk about anti-semitism or you
talk about the Semites themselves,
right?
>> Right. Right.
>> If you put a Palestinian and a real
Israeli or a real Jew next to one
another,
>> you can't tell them apart. No, you
can't.
>> They're the same people.
>> Exactly.
>> But it's the European Jews that came in.
>> That's it.
>> That infiltrated
that land or that area. And a lot of
governments, whether it's the United
States government, the European
government,
and completely screwed everything up.
And in fact, it's gotten even worse over
the last 20 or 25 years because of this
massive influx of Jews from Russia and
Ukraine. So, it's pushed the Israeli
electorate even further to the right.
But you're you're absolutely right. It
was I mean, people they hated the
British, of course, because the British
were the colonial power, but they got
along with each other. They worked
together. They all owned land and
cultivated oranges and olives and you
know
>> Yeah. Now you fast forward to 2001. Bush
is in office and on September 11th an
attack takes place
>> where two very very historic buildings
collapse
>> after two planes allegedly crash into
the building. The owner of the building
happened to have pulled out a very hefty
insurance policy prior to the attacks.
Yeah.
>> A what do they call it? A terrorist uh
>> terrorist clause.
>> Clause.
>> Yeah. Terrorist insurance is a writer.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. As Joe said, a terrorist insurance
clause.
>> These planes clash crash into the
building.
>> What was his name? Mr. Larry
Silverstein.
>> Silverstein. Silverstein.
>> Silverstein. Silverman. Something like
Silverstein. And he had asbestos
throughout the building that was going
to cost him billions of dollars.
>> Yeah, he was. But anyways,
the planes crash into the building. The
buildings are on fire. Hundreds of
thousand if not thousands of people are
in scramble mode
>> trying to evac evacuate the building.
The fire fire department is there. At
the time when the attacks took place,
there was so many different stories
being told on ground zero where people
were talking about, I heard bombs,
>> right?
>> Somebody said there was no plane. I saw
a missile.
>> Of course, there were planes.
>> But anyways, these buildings now
collapse.
Building number seven, which was not
attacked at all, not hit
>> that collapses and all of a sudden
there's a big outbreak as far as all
right, you know what? We were attacked
by terrorists. It was the Saudis. It was
a bunch of al-Qaeda members. We happened
to have found a passport
on a domestic flight, which you don't
really need a passport. Fully intact by
a Saudi pilot. uh we're going we're
going to we're going to war with uh
Afghanistan. But at the same time, when
you go back,
>> but it wasn't exactly that clear-cut,
though. The intent was not to go to war
with Afghanistan.
>> What was the intent?
>> The intent was to destroy al-Qaeda,
>> which was created by who?
>> Not the United States. That is a very
common misconception.
>> Is it?
>> Yeah. cuz I' I've the stories we've
heard is al-Qaeda was created by the
United States and again allegedly
>> uh in order to fight the Soviets.
>> No, al-Qaeda came to Afghanistan after
the US pulled out. The Soviets were
already gone when al-Qaeda went to
Afghanistan. The US pulled out at the
end of 1987, early 1988.
>> And al-Qaeda or what we used to call the
the Afghan Arabs,
>> some of them were already there and just
remained. But al-Qaeda itself went in in
the early 1990s.
>> Wasn't al-Qaeda, according to your
story, created by Osama bin Laden.
>> Yes.
>> Because
And but Osama created al-Qaeda and they
fought with the Soviets and then he also
wanted to fight
>> not as al-Qaeda.
They fought as mujahedin.
>> Oh, as mujaheden.
>> Yeah.
>> It was with Iraq that he wanted to fight
as al-Qaeda. Is that what it was in the
'9s? Because I know he had issues. Osama
bin Laden had issues with Saddam
Hussein.
>> Yeah, he hated Saddam Hussein as much as
he hated us.
>> Yeah, because Saddam also uh Saddam was
that that was at the period where Saddam
wanted to attack Kuwait.
>> Well, that was before al-Qaeda was
founded. Saddam attacked Kuwait on on
August the 2nd, 1990.
>> Mhm.
>> But it had nothing to do with religion
or Afghanistan or the Soviet Union. It
it was about oil. Yeah,
>> this the Kuwaitis there's a there's a an
oil field called the Romela field
>> that like 98% of it it's very long and
narrow it looks like Chile and 98% of it
is in Iraq and just the southernmost tip
of it crosses the border into Kuwait and
the Kuwaitis were slant drilling
so they went under the Iraqi border and
they were stealing the oil and so they
got caught the Iraqis caught
And so the Iraqis uh started, you know,
rattling their sabers and uh threatening
the Kuwaitis.
Finally, they invaded on August the
second. And most everybody just assumed
they're going to take that little 2%
across the border and that's going to be
the end of it. Most people didn't expect
that they're going to take the whole of
Kuwait and they did it in under 24
hours.
But then I mean even back then Osama bin
Laden was to the best of my recollection
he was still in Saudi Arabia 1990 he
went to Sudan.
We asked the Sudinis to throw him out.
He briefly went to gutter and the
Clinton administration asked the guties
to grab him. He was at the airport
transiting and we asked him the
gutteries to grab him and they said okay
but we need charging documents. What
crime has he been charged with? Well cuz
we're idiots. We had never charged him
with a crime. There wasn't even a grand
jury that had been assembled. So, we
said, "We don't have a crime." They
said, "We can't just kidnap him." And
so, they let him go. And he went on to
Afghanistan. So, he got to Afghanistan,
I'm going to say, in 95,
96, something like that.
>> But there's a lot of rumors that he was
also somehow linked to the CIA. Is that
>> is there any truth to that?
>> No. cuz his I think his hatred towards
the US came in because he his father was
a contractor who worked Oh,
>> his father was was Abd Rahman bin Laden.
He was one of the richest men in the
world. Not just a contractor like the
contractor for the whole Middle East.
You want to build an airport or an
interstate highway system, you went to
Bin Laden Construction.
>> And he was the one who built all the
refineries for the California company
that moved there in the 30s.
>> A Ramco that became a Ramco. Yeah,
>> the Arab American Oil Company.
>> But going back to where the conversation
began as far as 9/11 is concerned,
>> how much US involvement was there in the
tax in the attacks of 9/11?
>> I honestly don't believe that there was
official US involvement.
>> You do you really think that we were
attacked by
>> Yeah, I do. Now, I can't I'm not an
architect. I can't say you know building
7 I don't know control demolitions. You
hear all these different things. I've
also heard the Saudi royal family did
it. The Bush family did it. The space
aliens did it. Uh the Jews did it. The
Israeli government did it. Everybody's
got a theory. But I'm telling you, in
that year before 9/11 at the CIA, we
were panicstricken
because we knew a major attack was
coming and we had no idea when and
where.
>> Have you ever been to the Pentagon?
>> Oh, a thousand times. Is Pentagon
considered one of the, if not the most
secured building in the world?
>> No.
>> No. You can drive right up to it
>> and you can just go inside?
>> No, you can't go inside anymore. I mean,
you could before 9/11. Sure.
>> There was even a barber shop there. You
could just go get your haircut at the
barber shop.
>> But inside the Pentagon?
>> Yeah. My cousin Angela was was a barber
there for years, 30 years.
>> But as far as like security cameras and
all, did it exist during 9/11?
>> Yeah. So, how come we don't have any
footage of the
>> Because they because they never released
it. But you're also discounting the
literally tens of thousands of people,
including my best friend
>> who were sitting in rush hour traffic
watching that plane fly right into the
side of the building.
>> We haven't seen a single clip of
>> because they haven't released the
>> No, no. as far as like let's say from
your best friend or from somebody
because there's thousands of clips of
the planes flying into the uh
>> Yeah, there were no camera phones back
then and you're not driving, you know,
in rush hour like this just in case a
plane flies into the side of the
building.
>> People were just sitting in rush hour
traffic.
>> There was no even debris though.
>> Sure, there was plane plane parts.
>> Sure. The plane hit the ground and
skidded into the side of the building.
There was debris all over the place. It
took weeks to clean it up. I live in
Arlington. We were down there every
single day.
See,
>> I don't remember seeing any clips of any
debris back there.
>> But this is this is part of the the
danger is the years pass and people
forget some of the details. You know, we
we latch on to these ideas or theories
>> and we just forget about what it was
when it was actually playing out.
Cuz some of these when you look at a
when you look at how a plane is built, a
lot of it is like fiberglass and uh
obviously there's
>> very thin aluminum
>> aluminum and
>> how does something like that fly into a
building and take down concrete, steel,
glass?
>> But do you remember though when it first
hit, it actually didn't penetrate beyond
the first ring. It didn't it didn't take
out the building. It was that almost
V-shaped hole.
>> Yeah.
>> In the first of the five rings and
didn't penetrate beyond that.
>> But then you look at the same plane if
well if not actually more advanced
recently in India that took off and then
it crashed into a building. The plane
was still intact. There was a lot of the
plane that was still somewhat standing
>> and the building didn't collapse.
>> And the building didn't collapse either.
And it was a much older building as
well.
>> Yeah.
>> But all of a sudden that one plane was
able to take down
>> that steel structure. That's where the
question about the World Trade Center.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know. I had somebody describe it
to me as as like a tin can.
>> Right. If you've got a tin can and you
push down on the top, it's strong. You
can't smash it. If you put a little
[__] in the side and push down, you can
smash it. But how many floors is the to
How many floors is the World Trade Or
like 105 or 110 something like that?
>> And it wasn't like it was hit right in
the middle. It was hit at the top.
>> Yeah.
>> So you're telling me that top portion
was able to completely demo it to the
ground.
>> Like I say, I'm not an architect or
engineer, but
>> that was my understanding,
>> you know, and you hear you you don't
hear very often anymore. There was this
line of of theory about thermite paint
and nanoothermite and all this [__] that
doesn't exist that people ran with for
years like, "Oh, they painted with
explosive paint. It had thermite in it."
It's like, no.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Those those were a little
bit over the edge.
>> There was a lot of people that
interviewed weeks after or years after
that said, "We heard a lot of dynamites
and kind of like, you know, how they um
>> Yeah. I mean, how easy how would it be?
How easy would it be
>> to just to just
>> in this chaos that's happening that day,
you hear an explosion and you just
assume it's dynamite?
I mean, has there ever been any dynamite
that was found or dynamite residue? No,
>> it can be. Yeah. No, I look, I I
completely understand what you're
saying.
>> Dynamite residue that we know of. I
mean, who's doing the investigation at
the end of the day?
>> Yeah. I mean, but
what what's the evidence that
>> what what they want us to see, they'll
allow us to see. What they don't want to
see, we won't see.
>> Let's let's look at the issue of the
controlled demolition.
>> Yeah.
>> Do you know how long it would take and
how much work it would entail to wire
those buildings with explosives? And not
a single person ever noticed ever that,
oh, they're wiring the entire buildings
to be detonated. Well, the the stories
behind that were that there was a lot of
construction being taking there was a
lot of construction taking place
>> late nights when everybody was exiting
the building. So whether it was the
asbestous testing that they were doing
or strapping dynamite to the building,
nobody knows. Again, these are
>> I hate saying the word, these are
conspiracy theories that take place
where you just look back and you say,
"All right, what really did happen?" and
you and you ask these questions and it's
it's all dialogue at the end of the day
where you have this conversation with
different people and you get different
perspectives but obviously there are
people that go to the extreme
the paint that you mentioned right it's
like dude all right calm down with with
the whole paint
>> nanoothermite paint but then at the same
time you look at other things and it's
logical where you're like dude please
please explain to me how that top of the
building
how do you explain building was also had
had a giant tank underneath it. That was
the that was the emergency fuel
>> and that
>> uh for uh what was it NYPD or for the
city of New York or whatever it is held
thousands and thousands of gallons of
fuel. I don't know. I'm just saying
>> cuz cuz look, you've in in recent
interviews you've mentioned how you
think what Mossad pulled off with the
whole pager bombs is probably the most
brilliant thing ever.
>> Absolutely brilliant. So you don't think
for example they had the capacity to to
put up some uh demolition?
>> No.
>> How would they do that?
>> How did they pull off this whole pager
thing?
>> Oh, I mean there's a big difference.
There's a big difference between taking
10 years to take over the supply chain
than to go into the World Trade Center
and start wiring it for demolition.
There's huge difference. And and I I
come back to what they told us in in our
very first day of CIA analytic training.
You have to lay out the evidence. It's
one thing to say, "Oh, dancing
Israelis."
Okay. Well, what the [__] that
supposed to mean, dancing? Yeah, there
were dancing Israelis. You know why they
were dancing? Because they knew that
those attacks meant we were going to
start killing thousands and thousands of
Muslims. That's why they were dancing.
>> Yeah. There was interviews as well of
individuals at ground zero where they
asked them, you know, what do you think
about the events that took place? And
there were Israelis, Jewish women and
men who were smiling from ear to ear
saying,
>> absolutely they were. And now then now
the United States sees what we're we've
been going through and we get it. But
>> yeah,
>> for them it's like
>> I don't know, man.
>> But again, I come back to evidence.
These are all interesting theories, but
you got to lay out the evidence. And and
every time somebody says to me, "Oh, it
was the Mossad." Somebody else says to
me, "It was the Bush family or it was
the Saudi royal family. They're all
evil." Okay. Well, who So, who was it?
Was it the Israelis? Was it the Saudis?
Was it the Bushes? I told you the Lizard
people came down and they did it. I I've
actually gotten that. I heard the FBI
did it. I heard the CIA did it. I'm
like, "Yeah, we blew up our own
building, of course." So, you believe it
was Bin Laden who did it?
>> Of course I do. And Bin Laden said
afterwards in an interview with Al, not
an interview, but it was a a tape that
he sent to Al Jazzer that they wanted to
wreck the American economy to lead to
the collapse of the United States and
that they were planning another attack.
His words, that would dwarf 9/11.
That's why we went after them like we
did. We were afraid of another attack.
Are you looking for a place to kick back
and celebrate? Well, the Glenn Arden
Club has got you covered. Upstairs, you
got a private lounge with a cigar room.
Downstairs, you got the Mooseen where
you can have cocktails and private
events. Hey, are you even hungry? They
got an outside pizzeria serving one of
the best pizzas in town. If you're
interested in becoming a member with the
Glenn Arden Club or booking an event,
contact the Wisnuts. We'll connect you
to the boys at the Glen Arden and you
can become a member here or host your
next gathering.
You know, I guess I kind of find it hard
to believe that
you believe in that theory. Why? Because
you yourself
were convicted.
Because you blew the whistle on
torturing strategies of the CIA.
>> Mhm.
>> Yet you still believe the theory that
the government has told us via the
media.
>> No, no, no, no, no, no. It's not that I
believe the theory the government told
us. It's that I looked at the evidence
and came to my own analytic conclusion.
>> I just find it very even forget about
all these conspiracy theories of like
well the plane just
crashes into a building. I've talked to
many many structural engineers a lot of
them have said sure it's impossible for
that building to
>> Yes. But the thing is is there are an
equal number of structural engineers who
say those guys are just wrong.
>> That's what I mean. We have to lay out
the evidence. But how do you because I
mean Osama bin Lad and yes he had a lot
of money. Um but to be able to pull it
off just like kind of if we compare it
to what happened on October 7th which is
on a much smaller scale than what took
place on 911 as far as the damage that
it caused. More people have been killed
unfortunately
um between October 7th and today
>> many many more. But to believe that for
instance Mossad had no idea that the
that Hamas was going to attack I don't
believe that for a second.
>> So then how do you believe that al-Qaeda
could have attacked or Osama bin Laden
could have attacked us via airplanes and
we had no idea because I listened to the
intercepts. I was reading the
intelligence. I was participating in
these meetings saying that this massive
attack is coming. We we have to figure
out how to head it off. It's all based
on the evidence. Do you see the CIA at
the time is roughly around 50 years old?
>> Yeah. Right.
>> And 53.
>> Yeah. Rough roughly. Yeah.
>> And with the amount of experience that
they have, how do you miss an attack
like that? Do you think it was willing,
it was willfully missed or do you think
it was
>> No. See, this is another misconception.
>> Another misconception is that the United
States the United States needs a
propagation. Sorry, let me rephrase
that. That the United States needs a
provocation to go out and start killing
people. Like, oh, you know, we would
really like to kill lots of Muslims, so
we should attack ourselves. That'll give
us the excuse. No. If we want to kill
Muslims, we just go out and kill
Muslims. You don't need a provocation. A
false flag? No. The Israelis do lots of
false flags. We You know how complicated
false flags are? How many moving parts?
And you have any idea how [__]
[__] so many people are in
government? They're too stupid to make
to make a false flag successful. It's
just too too many moving parts. I think
we have a tendency to underestimate
incompetence in government. I really do.
Plus, you know, at the time, and I'm
actually glad you mentioned this because
this is a good time to bring it up. At
the time you had a White House that was
obsessed with China, that the fight is
with China, not with these these guys
wearing sheets. They're no threat to us.
You had George Tennant and Dick Clark,
who was the national security the deputy
national security adviser for
counterterrorism
screaming at Condi Rice that al-Qaeda is
going to attack us. And she said, "You
too again with this al-Qaeda, the
threats from China, not al-Qaeda."
And they wouldn't do anything. They
wouldn't increase the budget. They
wouldn't approve covert action programs.
They wouldn't do anything because she
believed, she was a terrible national
security adviser and an equally bad
secretary of state. She believed that
the threat was from China and that these
guys were idiots for trying to keep the
CIA focused on Arabs.
>> What if that was by design,
John, to keep to keep them
>> and then
>> in the dark?
>> And then who who would be the the
beneficiary though? Um
>> I mean condandy Rice is not this
intellectual giant who's going to you
know have a shadow government operating
behind the actual deep state.
>> Well I mean you have Apac right? You
have uh you just said yourself that
Israel Israel is more commonly known to
do false flag attacks. The owner of the
building was Israeli.
>> Let me interrupt you on that on that
score. I would agree with you as it
applies to Iraq because literally on
September 12th, there were
prominent
Jewish Americans at the White House
saying, "You know, we have to attack
Iraq for this, right?" Not Afghanistan.
>> Iraq.
Iraq. And the fact that that al-Qaeda
hated Saddam Hussein as much as he hated
us was irrelevant to them. I I'll give
you another example. Um you've heard of
Ahmed Chelabi, I'm sure. So Ahmed
Chelabe,
we have a little time. I'll tell you
little story.
>> So Ahmed Chel was um
was very unusual in that he was a Shia
Muslim Iraqi Kurd. There are like, you
know, a dozen of them. I'm exaggerating,
of course, but Kurds are mostly
>> It's a hell of It's a hell of a mut.
Yeah.
>> Yeah, exactly. Like a mut.
>> So, um, he his parents left Iraq in 1965
before the Bath party came to power. So,
pre-Saddam, pre-bath, pre- everything.
It was still a kingdom at the time. They
moved to Jordan. and um he went to
school in the UK, got uh an MBA, got a
PhD, and went back to Jordan and created
a bank called Petra Bank, and it catered
to Iraqis, Iraqi immigrants and
refugees.
So, the bank became like the go-to place
if you were Iraqi to put your savings,
your retirement, you had your checking
account. Well, he ended up just stealing
all of it, every dollar of it. And the
story is that he escaped to Syria in the
trunk of his secretary's car and made
his way back to London where he had
this, you know, $20 million townhouse in
Mayfair by Herods and, you know, lived
happily ever after. Well,
he started promoting himself as the
alternative to Saddam Hussein. Why?
Because he's pro-American. He's pro-
British. He's pro-Israeli.
And if you guys overthrow Saddam
Hussein, just make me president and I'll
give you anything you want. So in 1991,
the CIA created this organization called
the Iraqi National Congress. They
created it in a hotel conference room in
Vienna, Austria. And what it was
supposed to be was representatives from
like two dozen different Iraqi exile
groups. Every Iraqi who ever left the
country and had had a a position of
import in the Iraqi government, maybe
you were an ambassador, maybe you were a
general, maybe you were the head of the
intelligence service and then you fled.
You made your own little group and it
was in London or Brussels or Geneva or
whatever. They all came together in
Vienna and they all made up this group
that the CIA created and funded called
the Iraqi National Congress. And we
named Ahmed Talib, the director, the
president of the Iraqi National
Congress. King Hussein says, "Oh, no you
don't. This guy was sentenced to death
in Jordan for stealing all the money
from Petro Bank. There are thousands of
Iraqi refugees who are destitute now
because he stole their money."
So the CIA said, "Okay, how about if he
gives most of the money back and then
you guys drop the death penalty charge
against him."
The Jordanians didn't like that, but we
sweeten the deal a little bit and okay,
fine. They they back off the case
against Chelaby. So the CIA begins to
fund Chelby and the Iraqi National
Congress, 1991. And then we notice very
quickly that all the money starts
disappearing and that Chel's wearing
$5,000 suits and he's driving a Maybach
and he has a new house in Geneva and he
has a new house in Washington and we're
like, "What the [__] are you doing?" So
the CIA issues what's called a burn
notice on him. That's literally
everybody in the CIA gets an email or a
cable that says, "You are not permitted
to do business with this Ahmed Chalabi.
He's burned. He's dead to us. Okay, fast
forward to 2001.
9/11 happens. Dick Cheney says the
Iraqis did it. We said the Iraqis didn't
do it. Al-Qaeda did it. No, al-Qaeda did
it partnering with the Iraqis. We're
like, what do you base that on? You
can't just make [__] up and then make
create foreign policy based on, you
know, your fantasies.
>> Well, remember, we're talking about a
wararmongering Dick Cheney here.
>> Exactly. And so, so
Dick Cheney ordered us to start talking
to Ahmed Chelby. We said, "No, we're not
going to do it. We burned him 9 years
ago because he's a liar and he's a
thief."
But he's westernized. Yeah. The CIA had
enough. We lost millions and millions of
dollars that went right into Chalabe's
pocket. So, here's what happened. Cheney
creates a new position at the Pentagon
called Under Secretary for Intelligence.
And we said, "You don't need an under
secretary for intelligence because you
have the Defense Intelligence Agency
that handles your intelligence and we
work with them." Nope. We're going to
have a new position under secretary of
intelligence. And then we start
receiving at the CIA these cables called
DODIRS,
Department of Defense Intelligence
Reports. I'll never forget it. We start
getting these reports. I I was the I was
the Iraq briefer for the director at the
time, CIA. We're getting these reports
like, "You've got to be kidding me." Did
you see this, Dodd? It says that the
Iraqi station chief in Prague,
it was meeting with al-Qaeda
a month before the attacks.
Like, that's that's an act of war. Okay.
So, what's the source? It says a
reliable source. Well, at the CIA, the
words reliable source mean something. It
means you have formally recruited the
source. You have polygraphed him. He has
passed the polygraph. And the previous
information that he's given you has
proven to be true.
>> In short terms, it's a confirmed source.
>> Confirmed.
>> It's not a trust me, bro. Not one of
those.
>> So when we called the Pentagon, we said,
"We want to see the source." They said,
"Trust me, bro."
So, a couple of us went to, you know,
management, the deputy director and the
associate deputy directors and said, "We
think the Pentagon source is Ahmed
Chalabe."
And they said, "Well, we're not supposed
to, like nobody's supposed to have any
contact with Chelaby." I said, 'But
literally every intelligence report
that's coming in confirms what Dick
Cheney has been screaming about.
Everything. Well, you know what? It
turned out the source was Chelby.
They created the position of under
secretary of defense for intelligence
just to run the Chelby network.
And so
>> why didn't they just put him in charge
of
>> They might as well have make him the
Secretary of Defense for that matter.
>> Yeah, seriously. And so it was Chelby
and those around Dick Cheney promoting
this notion that 9/11 was actually
carried out by the Iraqis,
not by al-Qaeda or the Iraqis had hired
al-Qaeda to do it. And that was what led
to the decision to go to war. And mind
you, this is at the same time when Iraq
and al-Qaeda do not like each other
>> at all.
>> Because
>> not at all.
>> Because Saddam at the time, and these
are stories that were out there,
>> hated al-Qaeda, hated any sort of
terrorist group, and was out to actually
exterminate them.
>> Exactly. But at the same time, you had
other countries, including Israel, who
was adamant about us entering Iraq
because there was weapons of mass
destruction. Correct.
>> There was nukes. There was atomic bombs.
And
>> any day now, Saddam might lose his [__]
>> and push that red button
>> and nuke not only Israel, but all of
Europe and America.
>> I tell you, the Israelis were so gung-ho
to go to war with Iraq. They begged us
to let them send us.
>> When Netanyahu came to Congress and he
gave a big speech and everybody was
standing and clapping like he was the
freaking president of the United States.
>> I'll tell you, just a couple of days
before we attacked Iraq, um the Israelis
sent us a cable from Tel Aviv. And they
said, um, we want to be involved in the
invasion. And I briefed it that morning.
I remember it like it happened
yesterday. I said, we got a cable from
the Israelis. They want to be in on the
invasion. The deputy director
says,"Absolutely
not. Not in a million years." And I
said, 'I know. I already I already told
the the regional office that received
the cable. The answer is no. It's not
just no, it's hell no. Within 24 hours.
Well,
Iraq in the western desert desert, they
electrified the country, of course,
right? You you put up an electrical
grid, but their electrical towers had
three legs. Ours usually have four legs
in the United States. Theirs had three.
So just 2, three days before the war
started, every one of these towers just
started toppling over in the desert. You
know, you you can drive for 20 hours in
western Iraq and never see another human
being. It's just wasteland.
>> Yeah.
>> So they had run these electrical lines
all the way out to to the Jordanian and
Syrian borders.
>> The Israelis clearly had sent in teams,
sabotage teams. They put explosives on
one leg of every tower and for like a
hundred miles all the towers just
started tipping over. And I remember the
deputy director saying, "Those damn
Israelis, they just can't take no for an
answer. Like they had to be involved."
Even in the first Gulf War, the Israelis
came to us and we were putting this
coalition together to push the Iraqis
out of Quait and the Israelis like we
want in. We were like, "Are you crazy?
If you jump in, the Syrians are out, the
Egyptians are out, the Saudis are out.
Nobody wants you in. Just let us do our
thing and then we push the Iraqis out.
>> So, was it us telling Israel, don't send
troops in.
>> Don't send anything. They were like,
"Oh, we could send ambulances." We're
like, "No, we don't want anything from
you guys. Nothing. Everybody else is
going to quit if you guys get involved."
Well, then how come when we invaded Iraq
and we invaded Afghanistan,
>> you had you had Marines, you had the
army, you had the air force, and at the
same time you had the British coming in
there and helping us as well. So why is
it that the Brits could come and help us
but Israel who was adamant about
attacking Iraq and Netanyahu's like I
said at Congress at United in the United
States giving the speech saying we must
take out Iraq and get those weapons of
mass destruction yet they can't send
their IDF soldiers.
>> Oh absolutely not because because
they're paras. They're international
paras.
>> What about the British army?
>> Yeah the British army is the British
army. They have bases all over the place
just like we do.
>> So, how how was Israel our greatest ally
then at that point?
>> Oh, they're not. They're not. That
That's another That's another
misconception among the general public
that we're
that we're friends with the Israelis. If
you're in government, especially if
you're in intelligence,
>> you know from the get-go the Israelis
are no friends of ours.
No way. So why why is it that majority
of the United States continues to push
that narrative? Because that's that's
the power of the Israel lobby.
>> I mean today you can speak foul of any
country,
>> not Israel.
>> Not Israel. In fact, you know, there are
uh 34 states that have laws saying that
if you contract with the state, even on
a one-time basis, you have to sign a
loyalty oath swearing your loyalty to
Israel, not to the United States, to
Israel. I have a friend who uh was was
hired to give a speech at Georgia State
University, right? You go in, you give
your speech, $500, you go home. And they
said, "Well, you have to sign this
declaration saying that you support
Israel." She said, "I don't support
Israel." Well, you have to sign it or
you can't contract with the state. We
can't pay you. We're going to have to
cancel the speech. She said, "Cancel it.
I'm not signing a loyalty oath to a
foreign country. You go up to Capitol
Hill. You know, Senator Tom Cotton, this
[__] from Arkansas."
>> Yes.
>> He has the Israeli flag outside his
office in the hallway in the Senate
office.
>> How is that allowed?
>> Exactly. How is that allowed? There's
this idiot congressman uh from from um
Florida, this Republican from Florida
who a day or two days after October 7th
wore an IDF uniform on the floor of the
House of Representatives.
>> I saw that. I saw that.
>> What What have we Have we lost our
minds?
>> What happened to America First?
>> Exactly. I'm for America First.
>> Absolutely. And this has nothing to do
with the anti-semitism card that they
play.
>> Absolutely not. In fact, I was talking
to a guy just last week. I gave a speech
in uh where was I? I gave a speech in
New York at St. John's University and um
he's an Israeli guy, but he he he had
this like transformation. So now he's a
member of Jewish Voices for Peace, which
is quite active in New York. And he told
me he went he's an Israeli citizen. He
went to school in Israel. And he said,
"They teach us in public school in
Israel
to accuse anybody who criticizes Israel
of anti-semitism, no matter what the
criticism is." He said, "We're
instructed to call them anti-semites."
>> Well, yeah. That's their basic victim
card that they pull out,
>> right? Because it silences debate.
>> Of course, it it's like a yellow card in
soccer.
>> Exactly.
>> You did something bad. I'm going to pull
the card out.
>> Back out.
We've spoken about this whole
anti-semitism card that they play and
the victimization that they play and how
they bring up the Holocaust and you're a
Nazi if you speak up against us. But
when you as Armenians, the three of us
being Armenians, the Armenians went
through a genocide as well. Absolutely.
>> In 1915, 1.5 million Armenians were
massacred along with Assyrians and
Greeks.
>> That's right. We lost hundreds of
thousands of Greeks. Not not losses to
the point that the poor Armenians
suffered, but Yeah. So you're talking
about it was an honest to god genocide.
>> Yeah. Hitler said who today remembers
the Armenians.
>> Yet when you look at the countries that
don't recognize the Armenian side, you
would think that Turkey wouldn't
recognize it. Absolutely. Turkey
committed the genocide. That Turkish
flag is still around.
>> Azerban doesn't recognize it. But you
know what else? There's another country
that doesn't recognize it.
>> Israel doesn't recognize it. Have you
been involved in a car accident? Don't
face the aftermath alone. Arman
Gregorian is your personal injury
attorney who specializes in car
accidents. He'll fight for compensation
that you deserve. Call Arman Gregorian
now at 81844333.
That's 818-4433.
Why is it that Israel can't recognize
the Armenian genocide yet they play the
victim card as to we went through a
holocaust?
>> Yeah.
>> Well, so did we. You know, I think for a
couple of reasons, neither of which are
legitimate in my view. But on the one
hand, recognizing another genocide would
dilute the political power of the of the
genocide against the Jews in the Second
World War.
>> Well, what I'm about to say might be
taken out of context, and again, ladies
and gentlemen, don't take this out of
context, but we were only 1.5. You were
6 million. Why would it dilute it?
>> I know. Genocide is genocide.
>> Absolutely
>> right. I mean we have to learn from
these things and recognize them and
commemorate them. I was in Greece in
March and um and there was a huge uh
event set up in Simagma Square across
from the parliament. It's the main
square of the of the country, right? And
it was about the uh the Pontian
genocide. There the there were Greeks,
Ottoman Greeks that that lived uh along
the Black Sea. just 1500 of them left.
But we're talking about hundreds of
thousands of Greeks that lived on the
Black Sea in an area that used to be
called Ponttos. My grandmother, my
mother's mother's family came from
Puntos and they escaped in 1920, 1918
and made their way to Greece ahead of
the collapse of the Ottoman Empire when
they were massacring the Armenians and
the Assyrians and the Greeks.
Well, my friend that I was with had
never heard of the Pontian genocide.
And I said, 'You know, here in Greece,
we we teach it, right? Because you have
to learn from history.
Every Greek knows what happened to the
Armenians. Every Greek. Every Greek
knows what happened to the to the
Assyrians. How many Americans even know
what the word Assyrian means?
>> Seriously, they don't.
>> They don't know.
>> But also ask yourself this question,
John. Why do they not refer the
Holocaust to as genocide?
I think really it's because for so long
the Israelis were cultivating close
relations with the Turks,
>> which is why the Greeks were so pro
Palestinian for so long that I think
that that they calculated and we can we
can just screw the Armenians because
there aren't many of them. We're going
to go with the Turks and the Turks
aren't going to want us to recognize the
Armenian genocide, but the Turks are
going to sell us weapons and they're
going to give us a little foothold in
the Muslim world. I think that was a
very cynical calculation.
>> Why wasn't it called the Jewish
genocide? Israeli genocide.
>> Say that again.
>> I mean, not Israel. Why wasn't it called
the Jewish genocide? Why the Jewish
Holocaust?
>> Why was every Yeah. Every other country
that faced a genocide or mass killings
was called a genocide, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Not Holocaust. It's not It's not called
the Armenian Holocaust.
>> No, you're exactly right. That's a good
question. Um, yeah. I have a good
friend. um who I'm ashamed to say uh is
the attorney for the Turkish government
in in Washington and he's got a
Wikipedia page and on the Wikipedia page
it says that he is a an Armenian
Holocaust denier.
And I said to him one day, "Did you know
that on your Wikipedia page it says that
you're a denier of the Armenian
Holocaust?" And he said, "I am not. I'm
not a denier." He said there is a United
Nationsmandated
definition of holocaust
and it doesn't apply in the Armenian
case. The Armenian killings were a
genocide.
And I said, "Be that as it may, this is
a bad look for you." Because for most
Americans, the words Holocaust and
genocide are interchangeable.
just accept that a million and a half
Armenians were murdered. Just accept it.
You know, it happened. He's like, "No,
in law school they taught us." And and
he won't he won't acknowledge it.
>> He won't budge at all mentioning that a
genocide.
>> Chale Sen was on our podcast and Chale
Sudden ran into a friend from Turkey and
he would ask him as well. He goes, "What
happened in 1915?" And he said an event
took place.
>> Yeah. And that was Ottoman. We're not
Ottomans. That's not us. Could you
imagine, John, if the Nazi flag was
still flying around in Germany?
>> But the Turkish flag that massacred 1.5
million Armenians,
>> Greeks, and Syrians
>> is still up flying.
>> Yep. And it's always the other guy's
fault.
>> Of course it is. Why would it be?
>> Oh, no. No. We're We're Republic of
Turkey. You're talking about the Ottoman
Empire. That wasn't us.
>> So, change your flag.
>> Yeah, exactly. Change your flag. That
flag was flying in 1915 as Armenians
were being walked in the desert.
>> As Armenians were being
>> shot execution style.
>> That's right.
>> And women and children
>> crucified in some cases.
>> Yes. Women and children were being
beheaded.
>> Mhm.
>> There was It's sickening to say this.
There were pregnant women who were
marched in the desert whose stomachs
were slid open so they would guess
together the Ottoman soldiers as to what
the sex of the baby would be.
>> Have you ever heard the term janisary?
>> It sounds familiar.
>> The Turks had this this uh military unit
called the Janiseries. What they would
do um was they would kidnap Greek
children, take them back to Turkey,
raise them as Turks, put them through
this advanced military training, like
special forces training, and send them
back to Greece to kill Greeks. You're
[__] me,
>> huh? They were called the Janiseries.
They had no idea that they were Greek.
There's so many people living in Turkey
right now who have Armenian blood.
>> Oh my god. It's the same with I I belong
to these uh these uh DNA Facebook pages.
I can't tell you how many Turks who
said, "Oh my god, I just did 23 and me
and I'm 75% Greek. It's going to screw
up my whole world view."
>> I was literally just about to bring that
up. There was a video of a Turkish guy
who lived in Istanbul, which is
Constantinople, and he did a 23 in me
test, and he's sitting there staring at
his phone, and he says he's 95% Greek.
See?
and he's just like, and obviously he's
speaking in Turkish, but there's
subtitles and he's basically saying, "I
can't believe I'm Greek and I'm not
Turkish."
>> Let's dive into another subject right
now. We want to dive into the JFK files.
Recently with the Trump administration,
they declassified the John F. Kennedy
files. And everybody was super excited
to find out, all right, you know what?
what happened to one of the greatest
presidents that was going to I mean
hopefully finish his term but
unfortunately we saw what happened. How
much of the CIA was involved in the
assassination of John F. Kennedy?
>> Well, first I want to say I have a
friend at the White House and I
commented to him a couple of months ago.
Thank God that President Trump released
the uh the rest of the JFK documents. He
said no he didn't. I said, "Sure, he
did." He said, "Oh, no, he didn't. He
released most of them." And I said,
'Well, why didn't he release all of
them? And he said, 'Because the ones
that are still classified point the
finger right at the Israelis.
So, that's number one. Number two, to
answer your question more specifically,
I thought that what documents were
released were huge, right? There's been
so much speculation about CIA
involvement in the Kennedy assassination
for so many years and the CIA denied and
denied and denied and denied all these
years, 70 years, 62 years.
Well, what these documents told us what
there was that there was CIA
involvement. It may have been peripheral
on the one hand, but there are two
things that that are critically
important, I think. Number one, the CIA
lied consistently about its contact its
contact with Lee Harvey Oswald.
Consistently.
For all these years, they said, "We
didn't have any contact with Lee Harvey
Oswald." That is just simply not true.
We know now that James Angleton, the
deputy director for counter
intelligence, had ordered that the CIA
be in touch with with Lee Harvey Oswald.
We also know that Oswald, you know,
debated uh anti-Castro
people for local TV consumption in
places like Miami and New Orleans,
apparently knowing that those debates
were set up by the CIA.
So money was expended either to recruit
Oswald or to remain in touch with
Oswald. Number one. Number two, the
conventional wisdom was that these
documents would probably not tell us
anything new, but that they would
probably serve to confirm CIA
surveillance operations in Mexico City
in October and November 1963. And people
were saying, scholars were saying, okay,
so who were they surveilling in Mexico
City? And why were they surveilling
those people in Mexico City? We all knew
the likelihood was they were surveilling
Lee Harvey Oswald in Mexico City and it
turns out that they were they watched
him go to the Russian embassy or the
Soviet embassy. They watched him go to
the Cuban embassy was turned away from
both places but they knew about Oswald.
How did they know about Oswald? Because
they were working with him.
So that was very very important.
Secondly,
and this is the darker part.
This is actual CIA involvement.
I'm ashamed to say that there was a
Greek American named George Gianides
who was a senior CIA officer. He was
what today we would call the station
chief in Miami, right? He worked his way
up very very quickly. He had been OSS
briefly, then he dropped out, then he
came back in like 52 or 55, something
like that. moved up very quickly uh
through operations and ended up running
CIA operations from Miami. That put him
in touch not just with Oswald, but with
the anti-Castro Cubans.
It also would have put him in touch with
Santo Trafocante, the the mob boss that
controlled Florida at the time. Santo
Trafocante senior.
Um and with Carlo, what's his name?
Carlo Mar Car Carlos Marcelo or Carlo
Marcelo from New Orleans, the mob boss
in New Orleans.
>> Okay.
>> Um
the the scholars that I'm in touch with
like Jefferson Mley for example, I think
Jeff Mley knows more about the Kennedy
assassination than any other person on
the planet. Jeff always maintained that
there was CIA involvement in the in the
form of Georgees
and
It looks like he was right. It's not
that the CIA was involved as the CIA.
It's that elements of the CIA were
involved in the form of John. John was a
fascist,
an avowed fascist, and he hated Kennedy
and he hated communism.
And it kind of looks to me like he put
this secret group of people together and
helped to kill Kennedy. And it would
also explain why at the at the
at the what? You can't call it a press
conference. You know, when they when
they dragged when they dragged Oswald
out, he had been the cops beat him up.
>> Yeah. It was call it a reporter
interview.
>> Yeah. Reporters thing. And where he
said, "I'm just a psy." Well, nobody was
ever able to explain what he meant. He
was shot the next day.
>> Well, he looked super confused as well
when they told him president's dead.
Yeah. He he he was like in shock.
>> I'm just a psy. That would account for
it. That would make sense.
>> If he had been duped into doing it, he
would believe that he was a psy. And I
I'll add one third thing. Bobby Kennedy
Jr. is a friend of mine. He told me the
most fascinating story. And I said to
him, "You've got to write this down.
This has like historic import."
He said that on November 22nd, 1963, he
was in junior high school and his mom
drove to the school to pick him up early
because his uncle had just been shot.
So they drove back to the house. They
they had a big mansion called Hickory
Hill, just a quarter of a mile from the
CIA headquarters. And the Kennedys were
very, very close friends with John
McCone and Mrs. McCone. John McCone was
the director of the CIA.
Mrs. McCoen had died 6 months earlier of
breast cancer and John McCone had been
deeply in love with his wife and the
Kennedys were afraid that he was going
to try to commit suicide. He was so
distraught over the loss of his wife. So
they invited him to dinner seven nights
a week. So he'd finish working at the
CIA. He'd drive the quarter mile to
Hickory Hill. He would have dinner with
the Kennedys and then McCone and Bobby
Kennedy senior would go swimming
together. They had a pool, indoor pool.
So when Bob and his mom get out of the
car, he said his father's standing in
the driveway talking to McCone and he
heard his dad say, "Tell me your people
didn't do this." And McCon said, "I
don't know who did it."
The point being, he didn't say, "Of
course, my people didn't do this." What
would make you think that the CIA would
kill the president of the United States?
That's not what he said. He said, "I
don't know who did it
because he didn't trust his own people."
So with what we know now about Joanis
who died in like 1991
I think and never ever talked.
I think that an inference can be made
now that yes
even if it was unofficial
um unofficial
involvement
we could call it CIA involvement.
>> Now the documents point to as you
mentioned Israel. Yeah.
>> Prior to the assassination, correct?
There was conversations that took place
and this is all obviously documented
where
>> Kennedy is now pulling funds from this
from Israel. Correct.
>> He wants to
>> investigate what's really going on in
Israel
>> with the nuclear program.
>> Exactly.
>> Because they had been riding Kennedy to
give them nuclear weapons technology and
he refused.
>> So Kennedy turns around and says, "Well,
you know, there's a bunch of funds
coming into Israel now. You want a
nuclear program? I refuse to give you a
nuclear program. And in fact, we're
actually going to be
>> more or less uh auditing what's actually
>> he was considering sanctions.
>> Yes. Yes. Auditing what's actually going
on to consider these sanctions and then
boom.
>> He also told his girlfriend Mary Meyer,
Mary Pincho Meyer.
>> I thought you were going to say Marilyn
Monroe.
>> No. No.
Mary Meyer uh was married to Cord Meyer
who was the number three at the CIA.
Mary and Cord and Kennedy had all gone
to school together. They were great
friends from childhood. Mary and Cord
got married. Kennedy continued his
affair with Mary all through the the uh
marriage. Um, their marriage broke up in
the late 1950s because their 9-year-old
son
uh had been hit by a car and was killed
crossing uh Chambridge Road in MLAN. And
so, you know, when when people lose a
child, often times the marriage can't
survive. So, they got a divorce. She
continued to see Kennedy.
She said in her diary that three weeks
before he died, he told her that he was
going to break the CIA into a thousand
pieces and scatter it to the wind.
Now, he also told McGeeorge Bundy the
same thing. His national security
adviser Bundy wrote that in his in his
memoir. He had said it to other people.
That tells me he was serious about it.
that he recognized in 1963. This CIA,
this thing is out of control.
>> Now, if he's saying this to his
girlfriend who he's having an affair
with,
>> whose husband is the number three in
ex-husband is the number three in the
CIA.
>> Imagine who else he's been telling that
same story.
>> He was genuinely worried about the CIA.
They're out of control. They're out
there overthrowing governments and
assassinating world leaders and spying
on Americans. I have a buddy. He was one
of my first bosses at the CIA and he
told me that he started in the CIA in
the 70s as an intern, right? There's a
there's a classified internship program.
You have to be like really really clean,
you know, to get this internship. And um
James Angleton was it was like his final
year as the as the deputy director for
counter intelligence. He was a monster
of historic proportions.
So my my buddy starts in that office and
the secretary showed him around that
day, gave him a tour of the office and
he said, "When you first walked in,
there was an entire wall that was just
covered with shelves and the shelves had
file folders on them." And the the
secretary said, "Whatever you do, don't
look in those files. You're not cleared
for those files." Well, he's like, "I'm
22 years old. What do you think I'm
going to do?" He said the first time he
was left alone in the office, he went
straight to the files. He said every
single one of those files was on an
American citizen.
>> These are CIA files.
>> But why was Kennedy
threatening or considering dismantling
the CIA? Isn't
>> it out of control?
>> But the CIA director is hired by the
president. No. which is why he fired
Allan Dulles and named John McCone.
Allan Dulles was named CIA director by
Eisenhower. His brother John Foster
Dulles Dulles Airport
>> Mhm.
>> was the secretary of state under
Eisenhower. They were two of the darkest
figures in modern American history. And
Kennedy's like, these guys are just
killing everybody,
overthrowing every government that looks
at them crosseyed. I'll give you another
example.
um
Guatemala
in the 1950s. Okay. There was a there
was a wealthy there was a wealthy
businessman from Boston whose name
escapes me and uh this around right
around the turn of the 20th century and
he decides he wants to build a railroad
from Guatemala City to the coast, right?
so that his ships can dock there and
everything can be loaded and he can
bring the goods to to the United States.
So he hires all these poor illiterate
workers to just, you know, clear the
jungle and then lay the track for the
railroad.
every day when they take their break in
the middle of the day, they're picking
these fruits from the side of the, you
know, area where they're working. And he
said, "What are these fruits that these
guys eat?" And he was told, "These are
called bananas." He had never heard of
this fruit before, right? So he tries
one. He says, "My god, it's delicious."
And they're growing everywhere. and he
makes this decision that he's going to
buy all the land on both sides of the
track and he's going to sell the bananas
in the United States. So he renames his
company the United Fruit Company. Okay.
So
he ends up becoming the largest land
owner in all of Central America. And
it's all about the bananas.
By 1955,
the democratically elected government of
Guatemala says, you know, the Americans
pay us like a nickel an hour.
They take all our bananas.
They're making millions of dollars.
We're not making anything. We should
nationalize the banana industry and take
over this United Fruit Company.
Okay.
Who are three members of the board of
directors of the National Fruit Company?
Alan Dulles, the head of the CIA, John
Foster Dulles, the Secretary of State,
and President Eisenhower's Secretary's
brother. So what do they do? They
overthrow the Guatemalan government and
install a military dictator, which gives
rise to the term banana republic.
And the United Fruit Company under a
different name is still the biggest
company in Guatemala. They monopolize it
as well.
>> Kennedy's like, "What the [__] is going
on here?
The CIA can just overthrow a government
to protect the banana trade.
Are insurance companies giving you the
runaround? Stop stressing and start
winning. Public assist goes toe-to-toe
with the insurance companies so you can
get paid every single dollar that you
deserve. Fire damage, water damage,
storm damage. Has a tree gone through
your house? Public Assist has your back.
Don't wait. Call them today.
818-242998.818-242998.
Are you looking for a place to kick back
and celebrate? Well, the Glenn Arden
Club has got you covered. Upstairs, you
got a private lounge with a cigar room.
Downstairs, you got the Mooseen where
you can have cocktails and private
events. Hey, are you even hungry? They
got an outside pizzeria serving one of
the best pizzas in town. If you're
interested in becoming a member with the
Glenn Arden Club or booking an event,
contact the Wisnuts. We'll connect you
to the boys at the Glen Arden and you
can become a member here or host your
next gathering.
Knowing what you know now about the CIA
and the government cuz you know how, for
example, kids, young boys see police
officers on the streets, firefighters on
the street.
>> Sure. Or maybe they watch a war movie
and they decide, I want to become a Navy
Seal. I want to become a firefighter
when I grow up. I want to be a law
enforcement.
>> Knowing what you know with all the
stories that you have,
>> would you
want to be a CIA officer again if you
can do it all over again?
>> Absolutely not. And I wouldn't allow my
children to join the CIA. No.
>> Why is that?
>> Not only that, I I don't even think the
CIA should exist. You know, everything
is uh
everything that the CIA does is also
done elsewhere in government, right? Uh
the director of operations does human
source collection. Well, so does defense
human services. They recruit spies to
steal secrets just like the CIA does.
The State Department's Bureau of
Intelligence and Research, which is very
highly respected, does analysis just
like the CIA's Directorate of
Intelligence does. DARPA and NSA and a
half a dozen of other organizations do
science and technology development just
like the CIA's Directorate of Science
and Technology.
And for all intents and purposes, after
the 9/11 attacks, the CIA became a
paramilitary organization. Well, we've
got the Navy Seals, we've got the Delta
Force, we've got the Army Rangers, we
got all these different paramilitary
organizations. What do we need CIA for?
So, do you think the CIA is actually
operating as a fourth branch of
government in the United States?
>> That's a tough one.
>> No, I No, I wouldn't go that far, but I
would say that there is almost no
congressional oversight post 911. The
CIA can do literally anything it wants.
I can't tell you how many times I was
involved in an operation and a couple
times where the operation went bad
and then my director, my uh station
chief would say, um, listen, we we
probably shouldn't inform Congress about
this. And I remember being a, you know,
kind of a mid-career officer saying,
what's the threshold for informing the
oversight committees? you know, I
thought when something turned to [__]
you had to, you know, write a memo and
tell Congress. He's like, "No, no, no.
We're not we're not writing any memos."
Here's another thing. Let's say the CIA
has I I don't know what it the number is
classified, but I have no idea what the
number is. Let's say they have 30,000
employees. 35 40,000 employees. Okay.
The Senate Intelligence Committee has
40 employees.
the House Intelligence Committee, maybe
it has 50 and they're going to oversee
the the activities of 35 or 40,000
people. How's that possible? You can't
do it. So, going back to what you were
mentioning about Guatemala and the whole
banana republic, right? Do you think the
CIA has enough power to, I don't know,
interfere in United States elections
like they do in changing elections and
policies in foreign countries? It would
be highly illegal,
but sure, they have the power to do it
if they wanted to do it. And listen, I
I'm not gonna I'm not going to pull any
punches here. I think that they sure
tried to do it in 2016.
You know, when you've got the likes of
John Brennan essentially trying to
initiate a coup against Donald Trump and
to deny the American people
the the president that they wanted that
they voted for and chose.
Yeah, I'd call that CIA involvement in
America.
>> They were saying that it was Russian
involvement. It was a Russian Russian.
That was all a lie. And it's been proven
to be a lie. And then look at the Hunter
Biden laptop. You know, you have all
these guys. I knew every single one of
those guys, 51, 53 people who signed
this letter saying they did not say that
the Hunter Biden laptop was a Russian
operation. They said the Hunter Biden
laptop bore all the hallmarks of a
Russian operation.
>> So why hasn't the entire laptop
information been leaked out there?
>> Oh, it has. All of it has.
>> All of it. Every every page of it.
>> So then why isn't the media speaking
about it? Why is the Biden family?
>> That's the question.
Because if could you imagine if that was
>> Don Trump Jr. or if it was Eric Trump?
>> I have a copy of the Hunter Biden
laptop, hard copy. Uh it's been
published by an organization called
Marco Polo. Google it. It's out there.
They'll send it to you for next to
nothing. It will make your hair stand
up.
>> Yeah. This man was allowed into the
White House.
>> Yeah. Right.
>> [__] And got a pardon.
Well, he got pardoned right before his
dad left. That's right. Along with
Fouchy and a bunch of other individuals.
>> Sure. Sure. Yeah. The fix was in.
>> You should see the You should see the
pictures in this. Oh my god. And this
It's like, dude, did you ever go a full
day without smoking crack or having sex
with prostitutes? Ever one day?
>> Well, his son was a
>> and not take a picture of it.
>> His son was a hero.
>> Oh my god. Are we the only country
that's this corrupt or or every other
country is as corrupt as
>> No, I hate to say, but yeah, pretty much
everybody's corrupt
>> to this extent though.
>> Oh, worse. Most of
>> I mean, he's been to 72 countries.
>> Yeah, it's it's it's bad.
>> I can't imagine how much worse it can
get.
>> Yeah.
>> I think it's far worse now than it was,
you know, 30 years ago.
>> Well, cuz we have access to it right at
the tip of our fingers with social
media.
>> That's right. You're I mean everybody is
a walking surveillance camera at this
point.
>> You do something on the street instead
of helping an individual out, everybody
bust their phone out.
>> Exactly. And you have no expectation of
privacy in public
>> at all. But but you know what the but
the uh kind of the opposite end of that
is which I was thinking about it today.
I'm like with all of this AI technology
now, right?
>> That's the danger. the the government
can pretty much, for instance,
>> they can deep fake you right out of a
job, right out of
>> anything they want. Not only that, but
let's say if you happen to be right near
the uh Pentagon and you have your phone
out there and you're filming what is
supposed to be an airplane coming into
the building
and the government can say, "Well, no,
that's all AI. This Arno used AI to
create a propaganda against the
government." Yeah,
>> that was not an airplane here. This is
the actual clips that we have.
>> Yeah.
>> And then what?
>> So AI can be used
>> to their benefit in whatever sense they
choose.
>> Very dangerous development
>> and there's nothing you can do about it.
>> It's going to be the downfall of
humanity.
>> Yeah, I agree. This is bad.
>> It's dangerous.
>> And we're toying with it right now.
We're playing games with it right now.
We're using it as uh as a tool. It's not
a tool.
>> No, it's not.
>> And if it gets a weapon Yeah. And if it
gets smarter and smarter and smarter, I
mean,
>> oh man, I watched iRoot. I know what
happens when the blue light turns red.
Yeah.
>> All hell breaks loose.
>> Absolutely.
>> You know it's coming.
>> What was wrong with pre pre iPhones and
smartphones? Forget about pre- cell
phones even. But let's say before
smartphones,
>> what was wrong with us only being able
to get a hold of while we're in office
or at home? What was wrong with if I
need to send you an email, I actually
need to be sitting at my desk to send
you an email or to respond. And that was
the expectation.
>> One word.
>> What? Convenience.
>> Convenience.
>> [__] convenience, bro.
>> But that's they didn't create that for
your convenience. They fooled us to
think it's convenient.
>> Well, of course they did. Just like they
fool us with convenient.
>> Joe recently got the meta glasses.
>> Oh, I have a pair. I use it only because
when I ride on a plane, um, I I run the
the sound for the movies that I watch
through the medical. That's it. That's
all I do.
>> And and Joe got it for the show to do
like B-roll and stuff.
>> Cool.
>> And shower.
>> And shower. Yes. And shower. And shower.
But
>> when you look at that, they make it.
Look at the company they partnered with.
Ray-B bands.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, it's cool. It's hip. It's Ray-B
bands. Put it on. Look. Look. Yeah,
everybody's got them on. And then yeah,
you got a camera and oh, there's also
speakers in there where you could listen
to music and it's private. Look how cool
it is. But dude, come on.
>> Think about it.
>> It's dangerous.
>> Go down the rabbit hole, but don't go
all the way down. Just, you know, just
take a peek. Look down that rabbit hole
and you see those glasses. It is a
dangerous tool. Yeah, but that's the
thing. It's always, you mentioned it,
convenience. They sold us on the
smartphones due to convenience. they're
selling us on the AI due to convenience
because now you got to say hey write an
email uh for a real estate proposal or
LOI anything you want 5 seconds it's
there you just copy and paste it
>> and it's convenient but now they have
access just like with the smartphone
>> they accessed every single thing that we
do every transaction we make every email
we send every text we send now with AI
it's even more so so convenience is the
driving force and the selling point. And
we as the idiots that we are, we
>> No, no. We're consumers. There is a
reason why you can't take the battery
out of this thing.
>> You bet there is.
>> And also, when this phone dies, for some
reason, you could still track it.
>> Yeah,
>> but it's dead.
>> There's a backup battery behind the
back.
>> Yeah. As look, John will know this
better than any of us as far as like the
wiretapping is concerned. I mean,
how easy is it to tap a cell phone? Oh,
[Laughter]
>> that's the easiest.
>> I think they've been able to do that
since the invention of
>> I think when John walked into the
studio,
>> we're already tapped.
>> We're already tapped. They're like,
let's see. Let's see if these morons are
going to say to stupid. No, but in all
seriousness, if you look at the Vault 7
revelations that came out in what was it
2017 or 2019, uh Joshua Schulty, who was
a CIA computer engineer, allegedly
>> leaked these to Wikileaks and the poor
guy got 40 40 years in prison for it.
But he he told us things that the CIA
was doing that nobody had any idea was
happening. For example, the CIA can take
over control of your car remotely while
you're driving it.
>> Electric or any car,
>> conventional, really.
>> Boom. There you go. I
>> by hacking into the by hacking into the
car's computer system. So, why would the
CIA want to take over your car? How
about to make you go over a bridge or
into a tree?
>> Right. If you're a problem, into a
bridge abutment.
>> That's why I drive a 79 Cadillac.
>> Exactly. And that's the only thing you
can do to protect yourself.
>> See, I I we had this argument with the
boys like weeks ago where they were
like, "Don't get an electric car. They
could like they could gas it for you."
Or not gas it for you, but don't get an
electric car. They could basically drive
it for you. They could steer it for you.
They could stop you and everything. I
was like, "Dude, the technology in cars
nowadays, including gas powered cars, is
so advanced. The computer systems in
there are so crazy that regardless of it
being electric or gas, they can drive
you off that bridge.
>> Yes, they can.
>> Another thing that they can do is with
any smart TV, they can flip this the the
uh speaker
>> into a
>> microphone.
They can listen to you talking in the
room with the TV off.
And then you know what they did just
just to make it a little bit more
difficult were this to be leaked is in
the code for all this stuff they wrote
some of it in Farsy some of it in
Russian some of it in Chinese
thinking well if one of our people leaks
it we can say oh no no no it's not ours
look at this is the code's in Russian
the Russians did this they're doing it
we're the victims
oh my god
Yeah. I Nobody's safe. I mean,
>> no. Nobody's safe.
>> You know what's funny? We have 1 2 3
four cameras pointing at us. A TV that
might be an actual microphone. And we're
speaking into mics right now that are
connected to the internet
>> and we're complaining about
>> And we have phones in our back pockets.
Oh jeez. It's uh it's it's just a matter
of time before uh like all this just
[__] hits the fan.
>> Well, there's got to be a tipping point,
right?
>> Of course there is. But when is that
tipping point? That's what we don't
know. No.
>> But John, you had a story that when we
were sitting on the couch, you wanted to
say what was the story?
>> That's what I was trying to remember
this whole time.
>> Joe, do you remember what it was?
>> You you were going to say
>> we were talking about horses.
>> Yeah.
>> We're talking about horses and how
horses die
>> and I I said there was an article in
Vanity Fair uh a few years ago saying
that, you know, horses are very
expensive and you buy a racehorse and it
doesn't win. What people were doing was
they would take a light bulb and shove
it up the horse's rectum. Uh, sepsis
would set in, the horse would die, they
pull the light bulb out. So when they do
the necropsy, you know, the the animal
autopsy,
it just Well, the s the horse was sick.
It had sepsis, right? You don't know
that it was actually, you know,
assassinated. Yeah.
>> And then you can collect the uh
insurance. And I said,
>> I was in prison with a guy who was the
meth king. This is what he called
himself. He was the meth king of
Kentucky.
And uh I said, "Well, what exactly does
that mean?" He said, "I literally
controlled all of the meth trade in
Kentucky."
And we became kind of friendly. He was
the white shot collar is what he was.
So, um
I says, "Well, what how do you become
the meth king? Do you you have like labs
set up?" And he said, "Oh, no, no. We
didn't actually make any of that meth.
Only like these toothless losers make
make the meth." and it's not even
crystal clear. It's brown and it's low
quality.
He said, "I would get my meth from
Mexico." And I said, "And you were able
to cross the border with like large
quantities of meth." And he said,
"That's what made me the meth king." He
said, "I was a long-distance truck
driver, but I specialized in the
transportation of cattle."
I said, ' Okay, I'm not really following
you, but go ahead. And he said, 'Well,
that's the thing. I would get one of
these gloves that goes all the way up to
your shoulder. I would take hundreds and
hundreds and hundreds of pounds of meth
and shove it up the cow's asses,
and that's how I would cross the border.
The the DEA never knew that the cows
were full of meth up their asses, and he
would just cross the border. And I said,
"So, how'd you get caught if you were
the king and nobody knew you were
bringing in cows that were stuffed with
meth?" And he said, "The one thing about
transporting cows, it's like the first
rule of transporting cows is you always
have to be moving because if you stop,
the cows can't just stand there. They'll
die. They have heart attacks and they'll
die. They have to constantly be moving,
right?" And he said that he got pulled
over for some like random inspection and
they made him go into this corral and he
kept saying, "I got to move because the
cows are going to die. You got to let me
go. The cows are going to die." And then
one of the cows died. And you know like
a human being when you die your bowels
express themselves
and all this meth shot out
>> and he was caught. He was caught.
>> Holy [__] 20 years.
>> He didn't shove a light bulb up the
cow's butt.
>> That's what he should have done cuz at
least they would have packed the meth up
in there.
>> Oh my god.
>> And cause of death would have been
sepsis, not
>> and the cause of death would have been
sepsis.
>> Could you imagine? Like he basically
it's like one of those uh random traffic
stops where they just pull you over for
one thing and then you get caught for
the big one.
>> 10 different felonies for all the crap
you have in your car. The other day we
were here at the lounge having cigars
and uh somebody was telling a story of a
friend that supposedly this friend was
uh basically mule. He was bringing over
drugs,
>> right?
>> And one day one of those drugs ends up
somehow exploding in his in his body.
>> Yeah.
>> And he ends up dying from it because
>> OD. Huh.
>> Yeah. Yeah. OD from it.
>> That's terrible.
>> Yeah. Terrible terrible. Is there
anything we missed?
>> No, this was a good conversation.
>> Dude, I We got to have you back.
>> I'd love to.
>> We got to go to DC.
>> Oh, we got to go to DC.
>> I've never been to DC. I haven't either.
>> Seriously, we haven't been to I I'll
show you all around.
>> Really?
>> Oh, yeah. We'll go out. I'll show you
where the CIA is.
>> When's the best season to come to DC as
far as like the month and stuff?
>> Springtime.
>> Springtime's the best cuz the cherry
blossoms are out and they really are as
beautiful if
>> Cuz we know it gets humid in DC.
>> It gets terrible in the summer.
>> Yeah. Uh, you know, September and
October are generally good because the
weather's still good and the tourists
are gone, but really the very best time
is April. Okay.
>> And that's spring break for kids. No,
>> that's true. That's spring break.
>> Spring break. Okay. Well, maybe we could
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, we have your contact information
at this point. We're definitely going to
be in touch. I think we could sit and
talk to you for hours.
>> This was a lot of fun.
>> So much fun. John, it was it was a
pleasure having you here. We all three
of us appreciate it. We hope everybody
who's watching, you guys enjoyed this as
well. Again, if you haven't liked the
video, click that like button. If you
guys haven't subscribed, subscribe to
our channel. It helps us out and we can
have people like John join us.
>> Yeah,
>> this was a hell of a conversation. Uh,
>> and you're an amazing storyteller.
>> You are.
>> Thank you very much. Thank you very
much. You know, I I approached a
literary agent the other day. I've
written eight books and I only used an
agent for my first book, which did well.
I made number five in the New York Times
bestsellers list. Wow. So, I decided
because people tell me I'm a good
storyteller, I decided I'm going to
write a a big book and put all my
stories in one place. So, a buddy of
mine who's also an author um and a
former CIA officer, he's written
actually 24 books and like nine of them
have made number one in the New York
Times bestsellers list. He says, "You
got to talk to my my buddy. He reps uh
non-fiction writers and you two would
really like each other." So, I sent the
guy a long email. Well, I said, "These
are the eight books I read, I wrote, and
and I won these literary awards and all
this stuff, and this is what I want to
do with book of stories." And he's like,
"Yeah, that doesn't sound very
interesting, and I don't think you'll
make any money for me." I was like, "Oh,
okay.
>> Watch me.
>> Thanks anyway."
>> Yeah. Seriously.
>> Uh, but so I'm already 20,000 words into
it.
>> Beautiful.
>> I'll do it with him or without without
him. We we wanted to have this
conversation a little bit different from
the other podcasts that you've been on
as as you noticed. Uh a lot of the other
shows that you've been on, they talk
about
>> what happened with the CIA and the
torturing and all that. We're like, I
think I'm tired of talking.
>> Yeah. And it's like, dude, everybody's
heard those stories. We want to dive
into something where we can kind of
bounce certain topics off of each other
and get your perspective on it, which
again, we greatly appreciate.
>> I'm glad to have had the opportunity.
Thank you.
>> Appreciate John. Guys, today's episode
will be up and running on Spotify, Apple
Podcast, and all major platforms. Mñana,
have a great week. Have a great weekend.
I'll see you guys all next week.